Christopher Evelyn James

Belfast, Northern Ireland, United Kingdom



in linkedin.com/in/cjamesni



https://cjamesni.github.io



cjames19@protonmail.ch



+44(0)7902679405

Summary

Professional summary:

IT Systems engineer with 5+ years of experience in working with enterprise IT infrastructure and services. Specialises in IT system engineering, deployment, administration and automation. Special interests include: unix, linux & macOS internals, network routing & switching and automation software.

Key skills & experience:

- System administration of Unix and Linux environments supporting: *nix operating systems, Bash and Python.
- System administration and engineering of Apple desktop hardware and software applications for enterprise including: macOS, Xcode, Instruments, Bash, Python, Swift and Jamf Pro.
- Network administration and network monitoring for enterprise including: a strong working knowledge of common network infrastructure and network protocol (CCNA, N+ and Splunk certified).
- Endpoint system security management including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access & application control.
- Co-leading management of a global staff device collection and co-ordinating global operating system deployment projects.
- Client application packaging and scripting for macOS & iOS. Client application code-signing and enterprise distribution for macOS & iOS.
- Web application support and development including: customisation, configuration and deployment of a modern enterprise web service (VPC hosted with SSO and 2FA access) with supporting open source API connection components written in Python, deploying solution components to QA & Production enterprise environments.
- Version control using Git, GitHub and Bitbucket: https://cjamesni.github.io (My personal GitHub site)
- System engineering experience working with AWS hosted solutions supporting: AWS CLI, NGINX+, EC2 and RDS.

Experience



Desktop Engineer III, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services

CME Group

Dec 2017 - Present (2 years 4 months +)

- Primarily focused on delivering systems administration and systems engineering tasks for global desktop environments and IT infrastructure at CME Group.
- Specifically responsible for co-leading the management of a large staff device collection spanning the US, Europe and Asia, adopting a 'security first' approach.
- Standardising team processes and writing technical documentation.
- Research & development for individual and team projects.



Desktop Engineer II, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services

CME Group

Mar 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 10 months)

- Endpoint System Solutions Group member delivering systems support and systems engineering functions at CME Group.
- Escalation point for members of the internal customer support group locally and globally.

- Collaborating with teams from the Infrastructure & Operations department to remediate incidents of network, system or application(s) downtime.
- Managing endpoint system security, including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access and application control.
- Co-ordinating global OS deployment projects, including: Jira based issue and task tracking, creation and maintenance of Epics, Stories, Dashboards and Sprints.
- Preparing macOS application packages, scripts, security and system updates for global distribution.
- Managing and assigning site assets.

COBAIT. Infrastructure Support Engineer II, Managed IT Services, Europe & CIS

Cobalt Technology

Jan 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year 3 months)

- Disaster recovery operations including monitoring the back-up and replication of virtual machines from customer-owned production environments to a managed secondary site (using VMware vSphere 5.5 and Veeam B&R 7). Managing snapshots and restarting failed replication jobs.
- Escalating significant back-up and replication issues to senior infrastructure engineers.
- Updating back-levelled firmware on IBM storage systems and collecting DSA system logs for vendor diagnostics as required.
- Systems administration for hybrid Microsoft environments using PowerShell and Windows server administration tools.
- Managing client Active Directory forests including OU, security group, user and computer objects.
- -Managing client GPOs via Group Policy Management Editor.
- Lync server administration of online and enterprise voice users. Assigning telephone DDIs.
- Implementing Lync server QoS to improve communication quality.
- Exchange server administration. Managing user mailbox assignment, distribution groups and global address lists. Setting up Unified Exchange Messaging services.
- Managing SharePoint site collections. Provisioning site storage and structuring SharePoint sites including subsites, libraries, lists and applications.
- Troubleshooting and reporting on managed IT services for customers. Liaising with third parties to resolve problems.
- Supporting client's LAN networks.



Technical Support Advisor, Samsung Electronics, UK Customer Services

Teleperformance

Sep 2012 - Dec 2014 (2 years 4 months)

- Two years plus contact centre experience with the Teleperformance Group working as a technical support advisor for their client company, Samsung Electronics UK.
- Responsible for administering technical services and troubleshooting support for consumers of Samsung multimedia electronics products across the UK.
- Managing system configurations, hardware diagnostics, software updates and system recoveries.
- Explaining technical instructions to consumers via telephone, email and social media.

Laboratory Technician, Norbrook Laboratories Ltd, UK

Norbrook Laboratories Itd

Apr 2009 - Sep 2009 (6 months)

- Six months work experience as a Lab Technician based within Norbrook Laboratories Microbiology Department. I was responsible for reading and recording test data onto company paperwork, creating batch reports and updating company databases.

Education

The Open University

Top-up Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computing and Information Technology Currently enrolled with a number of modules pending.

Modules:

Software engineering

Web, mobile and cloud technologies

Data management and analysis

IT Project

Ulster University

Foundation (CertHE), Information and Communication Technology

Modules:

Systems Analysis

Networks & Communications

Programming I

Computer Technologies

Data Driven Web Authoring

Databases

Licenses & Certifications

of Illinois UC - Coursera Course Certificates

JZ7PVQCVUZ2G



VCAD510: VMware Certified Associate in Data Center Virtualization - VMware

Issued Mar 2015 - Expires Mar 2017 15811506-A547-E8A8D8E0E7A6

N10-006: CompTIA Network+ CE - CompTIA

Issued Oct 2015 - Expires Oct 2018 289267117-47687342

≡XIN ITIL® V3 Foundation Certification in IT Service Management - EXIN

5406360.20418524

Jamf CCA: Certified Casper Administrator - Jamf

Cloud Computing Applications, Part 2: Big Data and Applications in the Cloud by University of Illinois UC - Coursera Course Certificates

J2AHP62LR3YM

Splunk Certified User - Splunk

Cert-192053

200-125 CCNA: Routing and Switching - Cisco

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023 2X4GL4XJ9PFQ15GK

200-301 CCNA: Implementing and Administering Cisco Solutions - Cisco

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023

F3SKBLDD8DF4Q2WP

Honors & Awards

- **CME Group Excellence Award, October 2016** Ryan Eavy, Dir Technology Architecture Awarded in recognition of contribution to the research and development of emerging technology at CME Group.
- **CME Group Excellence Award, July 2017** Peter Metzke, Dir Systems Engineering Awarded in recognition of delivering several high profile items and services on behalf of Desktop Systems Engineering at CME Group.
- **CME Group Excellence Award, August 2017** Peter Campbell, Business Operations Awarded in recognition of a great ability, approach and professional demeanour in delivering ESSG services under pressure at CME Group.

Skills

Bash • Network Engineering • Systems Engineering • Troubleshooting • System Administration • Network Administration • Virtualization • System Deployment • Shell Scripting • Internet Protocol Suite (TCP/IP)